railso.com 2017-09-25

# Privacy e Cookies Policy - Railso.com

Every time You use this website You will be bound by the current Privacy Statement and You should review this text every time You use the website to satisfy yourself that You are happy with it. This privacy policy sets out how RAILSO.COM owned by So Magazine Srl, Via S. Martino della battaglia, 5a - 25121 - Brescia - Italy - P.iva: 03253930170 uses and protects any information that You give RAILSO.COM when You use this Website. RAILSO.COM reserves the right to use personal data voluntarily provided by Users, in compliance with current regulations ( _Articles 13 et seq. D. Decree Law 196/2003_ ). Users are therefore invited to visit this section regurarly for updates on changes related to the current legislation.  
RAILSO.COM may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes.   
RAILSO.COM is committed to ensuring that Your privacy is protected. Should we ask You to provide certain information by which You can be identified when using this website, then You can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.  
Personal data will be processed by RAILSO.COM through the use of both paper and electronic instruments, in compliance with current safety standards. The personal information You provide will be included in a digital archive for the purposes of:

  1. The development, compliance and enforcement of the purchase and sale contract over the products You have purchased or of any other agreement between You and us.
  2. Attending to Your queries and requests
  3. Providing You with information about the products of RAILSO.COM or of any other company belonging to So Magazine S.r.l. including, as regards the above referred products, sending commercial communications by e-mail or by any other equivalent electronic communication means (such as SMS).

RAILSO.COM owned by So Magazine Srl, Via S. Martino della battaglia, 5a - 25121 - Brescia - Italy - P.iva: 03253930170 being in charge of the file, undertakes to keep your personal information confidential and to ensure the exercise of Your access, rectification, cancellation and objection rights by sending a letter to the above referred address for the attention of “Marketing office – Processing Data Manager”.  
RAILSO.COM informs that users can exercise their rights under Article 7 D. Decree Law 196/2003 set below in its essential parts. Users have the right to require RAILSO.COM the following information:

  1. confirmation of whether or not personal data concerning him/her are in RAILSO.COM data warehouse
  2. the clear communication of requested data and its source
  3. the reason and purpose of their existence and their use

The Inquiry listed above may be renewed with a minimum of 90 days, except for the following cases:

  1. cancellation or modification of such data due to violation of the law
  2. deletion of data that can not be used for the purpose for which they were collected

Cookies  
We may collect information about Your computer, including, where available, your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration. This is for statistical data about how You browse our Website.  
For the same reason, we may obtain information about Your general Internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard-drive.  
Cookies help us to improve our Website and to deliver a better and more customized service. They enable us:

  1. To estimate usage numbers and patterns
  2. To store information about Your preferences, and so allow us to customize our Website according to Your individual interests.
  3. To speed up Yur searches
  4. To recognize You when You return to our site

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows You to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if You select this setting You may be unable to access certain parts of the Website or unable to avail of any of our services. Unless You have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when You log on to our site.  
SO MAGAZINE SRL ("RAIL", "we", "our", "us") and its subsidiary companies respect the privacy rights of its online visitors ("you", "your", "yours") and recognise the importance of protecting the information collected about them. We have adopted a corporate wide Privacy Policy that guides how we collect, store and use the information that you provide us with. As part of our commitment to your privacy rights and security, our website has been certified by VeriSign. If you are under 16, we require that you inform a parent or guardian about SO MAGAZINE SRL's Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions as well as requiring their consent to the Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions before registering with SO MAGAZINE SRL or placing and order with SO MAGAZINE SRL.  
Information as per leg. Decree 196/2003.  
Purpose and procedures for processing personal data.  
The personal data that you provide of your own free will, will be used to provide commercial and/or promotional information, with your express consent. The data will be processed for each of the above purposes using paper, automated and computerised methods, ordinary and electronic mail, telephone (including automatic calls, sms and mms messaging, etc.) And fax.  
Consequences of failure to provide data.  
Providing personal data is never compulsory, but without the data marked with an asterisk as “obligatory”, it will not be possible to provide the service requested. However, failure to provide data not marked as “obligatory” will not prevent the service from being rendered.  
Persons who may handle your data.  
Your personal data that are collected via this application, may be handled by people responsible for processing them, even from outside the company, and those responsible for providing the service requested and the envisaged marketing activities, and by the person(s) responsible for processing or by companies to which the data are disclosed as indicated below.  
Persons to whom your data may be disclosed.  
Your personal data may be disclosed to third parties to comply with legal requirements, to respect orders issued by public authorities or to exercise a legal right.  
Data controller and process manager.  
Data processing is controlled by the marketing office of so magazine srl  with registered offices in via rail via san martino della battaglia, 5/a 25100 brescia, italy.

Cookies Policy

WHAT’S A COOKIE?

In addition to navigation data, our Web Site, our mobile applications, social media and other online services may use “cookies”. Cookies are unique identifiers, which generally consist of small strings of text or code. As a rule, cookies are memorized on the device or in the browser of the User, and send certain information to the party that transmitted the cookie.

Cookies and other similar technologies are used to make the User’s navigation on the Web Site even more engaging and allow for determining the number of visitors to the Site, the frequency of visits and by what methods visitors use the Site, appropriately updating content, improving navigation, sending advertising information or strengthening security conditions.

WHICH COOKIES DO WE USE AND FOR WHAT PURPOSES?

We use the following categories of cookies on our Web Site:

NAVIGATION COOKIES

From the time of first access these cookies allow the Site to function correctly, and allow the User to view content on his device by recognizing the language and country from which he has chosen to connect. If the User is already registered, the navigation cookies will allow him to be recognised, enabling him to access the services of the areas dedicated to him. Navigation cookies are defined as “technical” and are needed for the Site to function.

FUNCTIONAL COOKIES

These cookies allow the Site to recognise the User in the event of successive accesses so that it is not necessary to enter data again with each visit (e.g.: ‘remember me next time’). If the User has placed items in the “Shopping Bag” and has then closed the session without completing the purchase and without deleting them from his cart, these cookies will allow him to continue shopping, finding the selected items again once he newly accesses the site (within a limited amount of time). Functional cookies are not essential for the Site’s functioning, but do improve the quality and experience of the navigation.

ANALYTICAL COOKIES

These cookies are used to prepare statistical analyses on Users’ navigation practices on our Site. The results of these analyses will be processed anonymously and exclusively for statistical purposes, only if the server provider uses the cookies in connection with the browser or other devices used to navigate on the site.

MARKETING AND PROFILING COOKIES

These cookies are intended to create profiles relating to the User in order to send him sales messages which incorporate the preferences shown during the visit or to improve his navigation experience. These cookies are useful for showing the User products of interest to him, or that are similar to those he has viewed, and are based on the navigation chronology of the User himself. The Site uses certain third party services which, entirely independently, install their own cookies. Third party cookies are those sent by third party companies we trust. These cookies allow you to be offered products for sale on other affiliated web sites(retargeting). As concerns third party cookies, the information on the cookies installed is provided directly by the third party companies, as described in the respective privacy policy of the parties indicated below under the link. The marketing and profiling cookies are not necessary for navigation on the Web Site.

SOCIAL NETWORK COOKIES

These cookies are necessary to allow the User’s social account to interact with our web site. Their utility consists, for example, of getting the User to express his appreciation or to share it with his social networking friends. Use of the data collected by third parties through the social network plug-ins is exclusively determined by the third parties. The social network cookies are not necessary for navigating on the Web Site.

HOW CAN I DISABLE COOKIES AND MANAGE MY PREFERENCES?

The majority of the most common browsers automatically accept cookies. It is nevertheless possible to manually configure your browser to not accept cookies.

Below is the procedure for managing cookies from the following browsers:

Internet Explorer: http://windows.microsoft.com/en-us/windows7/block-enable-or-allow-cookies

Safari: https://support.apple.com/kb/PH19255?viewlocale=en_US

Chrome:https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en

Firefox: https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences

Opera: http://help.opera.com/Windows/10.00/en/cookies.html

To obtain information about third party cookies, we note below the web addresses of the various informational notes and procedures for managing cookies:

Adobe: http://www.adobe.com/privacy/policy.html

Bing http: http://www.microsoft.com/privacystatement/en-us/bingandmsn/default.aspx

Doubleclick: https://support.google.com/dfa/partner/answer/186745?hl=en

Google: https://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/?fg=1

Yahoo: http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/uk/yahoo/cookies/

Youtube: https://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/?fg=1

For cookies collected via social network plug-ins:

Facebook information: https://en-gb.facebook.com/help/cookies/

Facebook (configuration): access your account. Privacy section.

Twitter information: https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170514-twitters-use-of-cookies-and-similar-technologies

Twitter (configuration): https://twitter.com/settings/security

Linkedin information: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy?trk=hb_ft_cookie

Linkedin (configuration): https://www.linkedin.com/settings/

Google+ information: http://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/technologies/cookies/

Google+ (configuration): http://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/technologies/managing/

Pinterest information: https://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy

To obtain an updated and complete list of cookies we ask that you contact us at the following address: info@railso.it

Cookies are used in every section of our Site and other services and online platforms: Deactivating them may thus prevent the User from using certain sections of the Web Site and the aforementioned platforms.

The user nevertheless maintains the ability to modify his cookie preferences through this information, which can be linked to each page of the Site.

For more information about cookies and to manage your preferences for third party profiling cookies, Users should go to http://youronlinechoices.eu/.

To deactivate analytical cookies and prevent Google Analytics from collecting navigation data, the User may download the browser add-on component to deactivate Google Analytics: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en.
